A Guide to the Warm Hearth Village Records, 1974-1982
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Warm Hearth Village Records, 1974-1982
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2007-002
0.7 cu. ft. 2 boxes
This collection contains documents related to the establishment and building of Warm Hearth Village a retirement community in Blacksburg, Virginia.
Warm Hearth Village. (Blacksburg, Va.)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated Special Collections in 2006.
Biographical Note
Wybe Kroontje was born in the Netherlands in 1922. He was part of the Dutch resistance during World War II and came to the United States after the War. He received his B.S. at Cornell University and earned his PhD from the University of Nebraska. He joined the VPI faculty in 1956 in agronomy. He served as the first president of the Faculty Senate at VPI.
Kroontje retired from Virginia Tech in 1987, and turned his full attention to the project he started with his wife Marietje in the early 1970s: the Warm Hearth Village retirement community in Blacksburg, Virginia.
Source consulted: Strother, Warren H., From VPI to State University: President T. Marshall Hahn Jr. and the Transformation of Virginia Tech 1962-1974, (Macon: Mercer University Press, 2004).
Scope and Content
This collection includes documents related to the creation of the Warm Hearth Village retirement community in Blacksburg, Virginia. Warm Hearth Village was founded by Wybe Kroontje (a former Virginia Tech professor) and his wife Marietje. The collection includes communication with V.P.I., designs and plans for the community, the projects HUD proposal, among other documents relating to Warm Hearth Village's establishment in the early 1970s. Warm Hearth Village is still in operation today.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in subject files.
Index Terms
Persons:
Kroontje, Wybe
Corporate Names:
Warm Hearth Village. (Blacksburg, Va.)
Subjects:
Blacksburg (Va.); Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Montgomery County (Va.); University History; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Contents List
- Appraisal Report, 1982 (Box-folder 1-1)
- Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 1-2)
- Design and Planning (Box-folder 1-3)
- Engineering, 1979 (Box-folder 1-4)
- Financial Statements, 1976-79 (Box-folder 1-5)
- Gerontology (Box-folder 1-6)
- Housing Markets (Box-folder 1-7)
- HUD Proposal (Box-folder 1-8)
- Market Survey, 1981 (Box-folder 1-9)
- Program Plan, 1974 (Box-folder 1-10)
- State Water Control Board (Box-folder 1-11)
- Steering Committee, 1975 (Box-folder 1-12)
- New River House (Box-folder 2-1)